[Music]
in Alzheimer's brains on autopsy markers
of mtor activation have been found to be
as much as aund times higher than AG
matched brains of those dying from other
causes that makes sense since nerve
cells rarely divide once they reach
maturity which would otherwise dilute
damaged cell debris autophagy is
particularly important in the brain
given the Striking Improvement in
cognitive function in Old Mice from the
mtor blocker rapy and studies showing
the prevention and possible Restoration
in some cases of memory defects in
transgenic Mouse models of Alzheimer's
disease there have been cause for
clinical trials of rapamycin for
Alzheimer's patients after all mtor
regulates Alzheimer's biggest risk
factor aging itself the risk of
developing this dementia approximately
doubles every 5 years after the age of
65 with the risk of death from
Alzheimer's skyrocketing approximately
700 fold from age 55 to 85 unfortunately
no such clinical trial has been
attempted it doesn't even look like the
dementia rates of organ transplant
patients given rapamycin have ever been
tracked when kidney transplant patients
are initially switched to mtor
Inhibitors they do seem to experience a
significant Improvement in executive
function memory and mood but that may be
in part because they were switching from
drugs like cyclosporin which can on
their own cause adverse Neuropsychiatric
effects Rapa has been off-patent for
more than a decade so drug companies can
no longer charge whatever they want
without such price protection there
isn't a strong profit motive to study
the drug so we shouldn't expect any
large clinical trials anytime soon
another reason for clinical trial
hesitancy may be the frequent and
sometimes lifethreatening side effects
like
immunosuppression in one cancer trial of
an mtor inhibitor for example two of the
18 patients developed life-threatening
infections and one of them died to fight
cancer or organ rejection we may be
willing to put up with significant risk
but there's a much lower risk tolerance
for anti-aging drugs meant to be used on
mass for healthy humans the mouse
longevity trials are impressive but
they're typically performed in a
strictly controlled pathogen free
environment that may not translate out
into real world conditions the
immunosuppressive effects alone are
considered sufficient to caution against
self-experimentation nevertheless there
is a clinic devoted to patients who
self-medicate with rapidy in an attempt
to slow aging rapy Advocates point out
that the doses required for anti-aging
are much lower than used in cancer
therapy or organ transplantation and if
anything might rejuvenate immunity is it
possible that transient Andor
intermittent dosing could also help reap
the benefits without as many risks you
don't know until you put it to the test
two small pilot studies of lowdose
rapidy for a few months in the elderly
didn't cause any major side effects
though did cause diarrhea and up to 62%
but also failed to find any immediate
benefits to cognitive function or
physical performance in 2018 however
hundreds of individuals aged 65 and
older were randomized to mtor inhibition
about 100 fold lower than what's used in
oncology or transplant patients and
instead of immune suppression they did
appear to get immune Rejuvenation not
only did they experienced an improvement
in their response to flu vaccination but
they experienced significantly lower
infections in the subsequent year
compared to Placebo and they only got
the drugs for 6 weeks this suggests a
persistent Improvement in immune
function months after discontinuing the
drug still self-experimentation
continues to be strongly discouraged
until we have a better idea of the risks
thankfully there are ways to suppress
mtor without taking
[Music]
drugs